Location: United Kingdom

Nationality: British

Date of Birth: 14/05/1973

Cell number: +44 (0)744 039 4411

Email: knight.pm.consult@gmail.com

#### **PERSONAL PROFILE**

Successful construction and fit out Project Manager with 20 years managerial experience working with clients, consultants, large blue chip contractors as well as specialist sub-contractors & service providers. Previously from a trade background, I am naturally proactive with a 'hands on' approach to management. Being approachable and of outgoing personality, I naturally develop good working relationships with clients, colleagues and subordinates alike which repeatedly proves to be a key ingredient to delivering successful projects within budget and on time.

Extensive experience and success in managing fast track, high end CAT A & B fit-outs as well as their integration with MEP, IT, other specialist trades and client takeover. Although spending the majority of my career in the UK, I have also gained valuable experience managing projects in the Middle East & South East Asia. Sectors managed include Health, Housing, Education, Hospitality, Commercial Government Services and Retail.

#### **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

#### October 2018 - Present - Extentia Group (Styles & Wood) - Manchester UK

Freelance Project Manager – Successfully managed a substantial number of delicate, fast track refurbishment & fit-out projects for Banking, Government departments & large Retailers. Left to manage multiple projects direct with clients & their consultants with full autonomy. Reporting to the Programme Manager.

#### October 2017 – September 2018 - CBRE Global Workplace Solutions – London UK

Freelance Project Manager – Client facing, managing Internal refurbishment projects within VISA Europe's "live" 9 story HQ in central London. My previous extensive experience in Design, Procurement & Sub Contractor management proved invaluable in delivering the highest standards of service for one of CBRE's top global clients. Negotiated further works for this client on behalf of CBRE. Reporting to Head of Projects.

\_\_\_\_\_

#### August 2017 – October 2017 - Paragon Interiors – London UK

Freelance Project Manager - Responsible for the timely completion and contract administration of a fast track shell and core Cat A fit out of a Specsavers store by Gatwick Airport. All aspects of QHSE Management implemented to the highest possible standards. Drove the programme and met the commercial targets. Reporting to a visiting Contracts Manager.

#### March 2014 – April 2017 - Kvadrat SoftCells – Middle East.

Project Manager – Responsible for the successful delivery of all sub-contracts throughout the Middle East for a high end, specialist supply and fit out company new to the local market. I managed the full processes from components leaving the factory (one in Europe & one in KSA), logistics, site installation and successful sign off with full financial responsibility. Managed multiple projects running in conjunction with one another in different countries with various degrees of complexity which were all managed impeccably by my teams to successful completions. I was also responsible for introducing and implementing an ISO Quality Management System to the company. Facing various clients including the world's largest energy company, Saudi Aramco in challenging circumstances. Reporting to the CEO.

#### Dec 2013 - March 2014 - ISG Middle East - UAE

Construction manager – Sole In charge of the fit out of a prestigious commercial Fitout within Etihad Towers. Works were successfully carried out via a number of sub-contractors in the live building to the highest standards of quality and HSE which worked in harmony with the landlord's strict representatives. The excellent standard of the overall process gained us further work within the building via the landlord's recommendation to new tenants.

#### Feb 2013 - Dec 2013 - Global Design Interiors - UAE

Project Manager – Successfully managed and closed out a number of office and retail fit outs as well as the refurbishment of a 5 star hotel's public, back of house and F&B installations. These from tender stage for various international clients and their consultants. Some projects were managed in conjunction with one another. I had full autonomy to manage the projects procurement, planning, Procurement and Implementation. All the client's milestones for moving in FF&E etc. were met as were the highest levels of quality, safety and site cleanliness as they always are on my sites. Working closely with consultants and suppliers, I brought teams together to achieve timely design and sample sign offs to meet procurement cut off schedules. Working closely with and reporting to the General Manager.

\_\_\_\_\_

#### July 2012 – Feb 2013 - TEX Air Traffic Control Services - UK

Project Manager – Fully responsible for the construction & fit out of Manchester Airport's new Air Traffic Control room on top of a new 40m concrete tower. I successfully managed all associated sub-contractor packages, contract admin and the hands on running of the works on site which was airside in this live international airport. I also coordinated with the client's consultants the transfer of staff from the old ATC room to the new and achieved a successful handover. Reporting to a visiting Contracts Manager.

#### August 2008 - July 2012 Carillion - UK

#### Project Manager - Commercial Design & Build - Manchester UK

Part of the management team on this full refurbishment of a 12 story office block within Manchester City Centre. Duties included inspecting & signing off services above ceilings in walls & within service risers, ensuring fire stopping was completed to the required standard and coordinated with final fix. In addition I managed the raised access flooring and the Joinery packages achieving a snag free successful handover. Reporting to the Project Director.

#### Project Manager - Churchill's Cancer Hospital - Oxford UK (third Hospital fit out)

Hospital fit out no3. Responsible for the fit out of a new PFI Cancer Hospital in Oxford with 2 Site Mangers reporting in along with all the various sub-contractors. Assisted and pressured an existing underperforming MEP contractor to employ additional technical design consultants to close out their design, and catch up on my restructured programme. I ensured the various tests & sign offs were completed in line with the finishing trades (this had not been happening previous to my arrival). In short, I coordinated the turnaround of this behind programme project to achieve the successful sectional handovers on time. Reporting to the Project Director.

\_\_\_\_\_

# October 2006 – August 08 Depa Dubai – Middle East

#### **Construction Manager – Dubai Festival City**

Responsible for the fit out of a 5 star luxury hotel in Dubai Festival City. Procured various subcontractors to increase performance on this heavily delayed project. I also empowered and supported my already existing site management team and taught them tried and tested methods to manage the site and contractors more effectively. This included introducing structure via quality management practices experienced previously in the UK with blue chip construction companies.

#### July 2005 - October 2006 Balfour Beatty - United Kingdom

#### Site Manager - Manchester Schools Partnership

Pre-construction coordinator from design stage to construction. My tasks included coordinating designers and consultants with the local council and head teachers to design freeze and sign off for construction. I also successfully managed controlled demolition works within some of the schools including the safe removal of asbestos. Reporting to the Project Director.

#### **Site Manager - Spring Gardens - Manchester City Centre**

Here I managed the day to day construction on site of a 15 story, steel framed commercial building including the subcontractor packages both on site and in coordination meetings. The project was built on a very tight plot between adjacent live buildings and overlooking public areas. I successfully liaised with neighbors and the local council departments with regards to road closures and the redirection of the public etc. I also worked closely with the contractors to improve their Health & Safety practices to the highest levels achievable on site. Reporting to the Project Director.

#### Section Site Manager - Queens Park Hospital - Blackburn

My 2nd Hospital project was in Blackburn, UK and had me responsible for the fit out of the largest section of the project. This included the A&E, radiology and class A ultraclean operating theatres. I managed the associated sub- contractor packages, implemented the existing programme, ensured quality on site and adherence to the Project Quality Plan. I coordinated the MEP and specialist contractors to work closely with the finishing trades to achieve pre-closure sign offs with the client and his consultants. All this whilst maintaining the highest levels Health & Safety. Reporting to the Senior Project Manager.

#### April 2003 - July 2005 ISG - United Kingdom

#### Site Manager, Medical School - Manchester University

Managed the complete strip out & demolition of existing labs, & offices over 3 floors from within the live University research facility. Re-fitted with new Class 1 Labs. Reporting to a visiting Contracts Manager.

#### Site Manager, HMP Service North West Regional Office – Chorley

Managed the Fast track fit out of offices spread over two floors. Reporting to the visiting Contracts Manager.

#### Site Manager, Greater Manchester Police Air Support Unit

Managed the construction & fit out of an extension to the existing Air Support Unit. Work was carried out adjacent to the location of the Police Helicopter which had to remain fully operational throughout. Reporting to the visiting Contracts Manager.

#### Site Manager, Richmond Hill Primary School - Doncaster

Managed extensions & general refurbishment of a primary school during term time. Reporting to the visiting Contracts Manager.

\_\_\_\_\_

#### August 2000 – April 2003 Morgan Sindall / Bluestone – United Kingdom

#### Site Manager, Whatman International Plc - New production facility in Oxfordshire

Managed the fit out of new offices, laboratories, ultra-clean rooms as well as the construction of extensions for hazardous waste areas. Reporting to the visiting Contracts Manager.

#### Site Manager, Warrington Arts Centre (The Pyramid)

Co-managed the refurbishment of two large existing grade 2 listed buildings & the construction of a new steel & glazed atrium joining them together and forming the new Warrington Arts Centre. Reporting to the Project Manager.

#### Site Manager, School Refurbishment & Extension,

Managed the refurbishment of an existing Secondary School and the construction of a new extension during term time. Reported to a visiting Contracts Manager.

#### Site Manager School Extension, Keighley

Managed the refurbishment of various existing buildings & the construction of new buildings. Reporting to the visiting Contracts Manager.

# Oct 1998 - May 2000 Amec Construction – Untied Kingdom Section Site Manager, Cumberland Infirmary, Carlisle, Cumbria.

Responsible for the day to day fit out management of the A&E, Operating theatres, Pharmacy & Radiology departments. Successfully sorted out lots of uncoordinated design issues at site including missing services and clashes leading to achieving sign offs and handover.

1996 - 1998 OWN BUILDING & JOINERY BUSINESS

1992 - 1996 SELF EMPLOYED JOINER & GENERAL BUILDER

1989 - 1992 HIGH GARTH HOMES LTD - Apprentice Joiner

#### **QUALIFICATIONS:**

PRINCE 2 Practitioner

SMSTS Certificate

CSCS Black Card

First Aid Certificate

ACIOB perusing full membership

Fire Safety & Fire Fighting Certificate

Scaffold & Harness Inspection Certificate Asbestos Awareness Certificate

Various ROSPA certs in Site H&S Management

Carillion Project Management Certificate

MS Office Certificate

NVQ levels 1 to 3 in Carpentry & Joinery